Guide to the Stanford University, Press, Records SC0656
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Press, records
1915-1988
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Press
SC0656
40 Linear Feet
Records of the Stanford University Press include correspondence files, financial records, contracts, inventories, reports, and other general records; minutes of the editorial board, 1976-88, the Faculty Committee on University Publications, 1945-76, and the Press Special Committee, 1927-45; press catalogs and newsletters; some production materials (including photographs and illustrations) and correspondence pertaining to specific publications; and various test forms, answer sheets, etc., for the Strong vocational interest blank and the Stanford hypnotic susceptibility scale, both of which were published by the Stanford University Press.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfer, 2000 and 2007.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Records of the Stanford University Press include correspondence files, financial records, contracts, inventories, reports, and other general records; minutes of the editorial board, 1976-88, the Faculty Committee on University Publications, 1945-76, and the Press Special Committee, 1927-45; press catalogs and newsletters; some production materials (including photographs and illustrations) and correspondence pertaining to specific publications; and various test forms, answer sheets, etc., for the Strong vocational interest blank and the Stanford hypnotic susceptibility scale, both of which were published by the Stanford University Press.
Vocational interests -- Testing.; University presses -- California -- Stanford.; Stanford hypnotic susceptibility scale.; Scholarly publishing -- California -- Stanford.; Publishers and publishing.; Book industries and trade.; Stanford University. Faculty Committee on University Publications; Stanford University. Press; Stanford University. Press
- Records, Accession ARCH-2000-079
  - Strong Vocational Interest Blanks (SVIB) Scoring Scales, Men A-Z and Groups I, II, V, VIII, IX, X 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SVIB Form W & Balance of Form M Reprints of Machine-Scoring Scales (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SVIB-SCII (Strong-Campbell Interest Inventory) envelopes – site licenses, Spanish, Swedish, SCII forms, Roche Testing Services, National Career Research Institute (NCRI) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - SVIB Roche computer program for scoring Navy scales (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - SVIB Women hand stencil complete set (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - SVIB Men Scales, Original 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SVIB Form M Reprints of Machine-Scoring Scales (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - SVIB Form M Reprints of Hand-Scoring Scales (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - SVIB Form W Reprints of Hand-Scoring Scales (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Press (SUP) Catalogs 1915-1985 (bound) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Keen, Myra A., Marine Molluscan Genera of Western North America; An Illustrated Key 1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - SVIB Women Scoring Scales (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sex-Fair Interest Measurement: Research and Implications (NIE, 1978) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Issues of Sex Bias and Sex Fairness in Career Interest Measurement (NIE 1975) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Computer-Based Career Guidance & Counselor-Administrative Support System (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - SVIB-SCII licenses, forms, brochures, answer sheets, scoring stencils, item weights (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - SVIB Manual 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SVIB-SCII Manual 1st & 2nd editions 1974, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - SVIB-SCII Papers and reports of Jo-Ida Hansen and David Campbell (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The American Personnel & Guidance Association Program Annual Convention 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Kuder E. General Interest Survey Manual 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Addison-Wesley Catalog of School Tests and Services 1978-79 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - SVIB-SCII Test batteries (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - SVIB-SCII Veterans Administration, St. Petersburg, FL 1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - SVIB-SCII V.A. Medical Center, Salt Lake (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - SCII License University of the Witwatersrand (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - SCII Counseling Center, University of Washington Profile (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - SVIB Vernon Psychological Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - SVIB Vernon Psychological Laboratory (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - SVIB-SCII Experimental Edition (1972) and Research Edition (1972) Test Booklet (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - SVIB-SCII Test booklets (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - SVIB-SCII Answer sheets (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - SVIB-SCII Profiles 1974 and 1976 revised (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - SCII T325 brochure (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - SVIB Research results, articles, Manual 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - SVIB-SCII Jo-Ida Hansen Annual Reports (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - SVIB Research results, articles on SVIB, Manual 1970- (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - SVIB A Bibliography for the Strong Vocational Interest Blank – Stanford-Campbell Interest Inventory (SVIB-SCII) 1912-1980. Center for Interest Measurement Research, University of Minnesota. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - SVIB and SCII: Evaluation Service Inc. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - SVIB and SCII: Evaluation Service Inc. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - SVIB and SCII forms: Consulting Psychologists Press (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - SCII Scoring Agency – Insight Centres, Glasgow (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - SVIB-SCII Interactive Enterprises Ltd. (Canada) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - SCII Interpreting Scoring Systems (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - SVIB-SCII T325 National Computer Systems (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - SVIB-SCII T399 & TW398 National Computer Systems (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - SVIB-SCII National Computer Systems, Johansson Career Assessment Inventory NCS GATB (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - SVIB Women Scoring Scales (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - SVIB-SCII Medical Specialists Preference Blank (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - SVIB-SCII Manual Supplement 1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - SVIB-SCII Testcor (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - SVIB-SCII Women Printings through 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - SVIB-SCII Women Printings 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - SVIB-SCII Men Printings 1966-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - SVIB-SCII MRC/Westinghouse Learning Corp. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Alabama (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - SVIB-SCII Brigham Young University (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - SVIB-SCII Caress, Gilhooly, Kestin, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - SVIB-SCII Central Intelligence Agency (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - SVIB-SCII Computer Printouts 1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Houston (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - SVIB-SCII Georgia State University (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Illinois (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Illinois (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - SVIB-SCII Career Guidance Center, Region 10 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - SVIB-SCII Career Guidance Center, Region 15 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - SVIB-SCII Klein Institute (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - SVIB-SCII Klein Institute (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - SVIB-SCII Career Research Systems (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - SVIB-SCII Ashland Oil Co. (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - SVIB-SCII Personnel Decisions (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - SVIB-SCII Ford Motor Co. (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - SVIB-SCII Life Insurance Agency Management Association (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - SVIB-SCII Motivational Training/Supervision (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - SVIB-SCII National Institute of Mental Health (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - SVIB-SCII Berman (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - SVIB-SCII J.C. Penny (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - SVIB-SCII forms & manuals (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - SVIB-SCII A-B Inventory Hand-Scoring Stencils (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - SVIB Men Hand-scoring Stencils (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - SUP Editorial Board Minutes Oct. 1976 – Aug. 1988 (bound) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Clark, A. B. Perspective, a Textbook and Manual for Artists, Architects and Students. 1936 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Barry, John D. Albert Bender’s Birthday. Roxburghe Club booklet 1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Seven Pioneer San Francisco Libraries. Roxburghe Club booklet 1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and thank you card (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Specifications and blueprints for alteration and addition to press expansion, Clark and Beuttler Architects 1961-62 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Photographs – SUP/Cambridge University Press collaboration ceremonies [2 sets] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - SUP news releases (re publications) 1940s-50s [3-ring binder] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Book Worm, Stanford Colophon (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Book-Keeping and Cost-Finding 1916 (bound typescript) (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Taylor, Edward DeWitt This Fortunate Man 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Pressing Business: Leon E. Seltzer and Stanford University Press, 1956-1983 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Hansen, Ralph W. “The Stanford University Press From Printer to Publisher,” University of California School of Librarianship L.S. 298 [class paper, no date – post 1969 from internal evidence] (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - SUP warehouse photographs July 1, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Woodburne, Lloyd S. Principles of College and University Administration 1958 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Harte, Bret Concerning “Condensed Novels” 1929 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Jay Miller’s retirement party 1971: film (color Super 8), slides, and audio tape (3” reel) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Stanford/Muybridge commemoration ceremony 5/8/1929 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - SUP Miscellaneous manuals, forms, contracts, price list (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - SVIB scoring stencils, forms, booklets, manuals, weight & conversion tabulations (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - SVIB James K. Dent permissions (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - SVIB miscellaneous publications (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Weitzenhoffer & Hilgard - Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale -tests, forms, charts (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Wrenn – Studying (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Index card files on SUP publications and reprint requests (out of order) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Scenes, 10 Views of Stanford in Color (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Committee on University Publications Minutes, Aug. 1945-June 1976 [8 bound volumes] (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
  - SUP Special Committee Minutes, Dec. 1927-June 1945 (Box 10, Folder 9-10)
  - Muller, Will, Olympic Country, typescript and photographs 1934-1938 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Price, John B., Familiar Birds of the Stanford Campus 1931 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Jordan, D. S., The Story of the Innumerable Company 1895 (first SUP publication) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Marryat, Frank, Mountains and Molehills or Recollections of a Burnt Journal 1855 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Clausen, Henry C., Stanford’s Judge Crothers 1967 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Research Work of the Stanford University School of Medicine from 1919 to 1929 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Sandstone Scribe (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Colophon history (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Stanford University Memorial Church (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Herbert Packer Memorial (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - SUP Sales Manager’s Report 1928-1929 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Stanford University Study of Printing and Related Services (Cresap, McCormick and Paget, Management Consultants Feb. 1969) (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Printing copy – L.E. Seltzer memoranda to Alf Brandin, Feb. 28, 1969, Mar. 26, 1969 and Apr. 1, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Transcript of conference held in Office of Business Affairs on Mar. 27, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Corrected draft of transcript of conference held in Office of Business Affairs on Mar. 27, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - File copies – L.E. Seltzer memoranda to Alf Brandin, Feb. 28, 1969, Mar. 26, 1969 and Apr. 1, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - CMP report correspondence 1969 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of party in SUP building (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Samples of SUP book plate and two printing dies (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Horsburgh and Health, Atlas of Cat Anatomy, 3rd ed. 1967 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Wrenn and Larsen, Studying Effectively 2nd ed. (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - SVIB-SCII Memphis State University (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - SVIB-SCII Psych Systems (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - SVIB-SCII Ministry Inventories (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Minnesota (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Mississippi (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - SVIB-SCII National Cash Register Corp. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - SVIB-SCII University of New Mexico (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - SVIB-SCII North Texas State University (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - SVIB-SCII St. Louis Community College Maramee (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - SVIB-SCII Southern Methodist University (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - SVIB-SCII University of Swansea (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - SVIB-SCII U.S. Naval Academy (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - SVIB-SCII U.S. Naval Academy (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - SVIB-SCII – assorted manuals (10 volumes; “most complete set”) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Videotape “Individual Interpretation Strong Campbell Interest Inventory, 1981” [3/4 inch U-matic] (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - SVIB – assorted forms (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - SVIB – assorted forms (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - SVIB – Sales & Printing Records (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - SVIB forms, Personal Data Blanks, Hypnotic Susceptibility (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - SVIB T399 & TW398 Item Weights Archive Sets (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - SVIB A-B Inventory 1969 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - SVIB item weights (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - SVIB correspondence (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - SCII PI in process (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - PI SUB-SCII Manual 2nd edition – correspondence file (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - SCII T325 1972 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - SCII Final Forms (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - SVIB miscellany (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - DOR Bell test and manual (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - SVIB Form M – Machine-Scored, Hand-Scored, Testscor and Klein Institute (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - SVIB brochures and announcements (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - SVIB forms (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - SVIB-SCII Summary Reply on Sex-Bias Charge (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - “Aguas Abajo” by Gloria Moreno and “The Cave of Salamanca” by Miguel de Cervantes Saavedra, both translated by Wilber E. Bailey, 1936-1942 (typescripts) (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Richards and Richards, Geologic History at a Glance 1955 printing (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Maslow, Security – Insecurity Inventory (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Maslow, Social Personality Inventory for College Women (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Otterstein – Mosher, Sight Singing O-M Test (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pond, Inventory of Reading Experiences (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Pryor, Width-Weight Tables and Charts (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cooper & Robins, The Term Paper, various editions (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Stauf, Ida, Outline for French Verbs 1929 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Starks, Edwin C., assorted dissection manuals (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale: assorted publications (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - SUP type faces: 3 binders of samples (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous photographs: Leon E. Seltzer, Sam McDonald, Donald P. Bean, and retirement dinner 1949 (Whittern, Ware, Thomson) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Paul Hanna & W. H. Cowley Addresses 1954 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Aerial photograph of Stanford University 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photo reproduction of Stanford University Deed of Grant (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - The Story of the Bowman Alumni House 1952 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - A Challenge to California and the West (booklet re proposed gift to School of Medicine, 1932) (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Staged in Arboreal Beauty – Laurence Frost Amphitheater 1939 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Buell, original pencil sketches for Time Line, California Stepping-Stones (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Ricketts, Between Pacific Tides – separation negatives, Chiton color photo for 1941 reprinting (glass plates) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Your Rugged Constitution correspondence (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Your Rugged Constitution and Crary funds – correspondence (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Your Rugged Constitution article in Shell News, May 1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Your Rugged Constitution Promotional Material (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - L.E. Seltzer memorandum to Alf Brandin re CMP report as it relates to the Press, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - SVIB – trademarks (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Ricketts, Between Pacific Tides Old Artwork, not in 4th ed. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ricketts, Between Pacific Tides Duplicates, not in 4th ed. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Buell, Historical Time Line of California Stepping-Stones (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - King, P.S. Stanford University map ca. 1959 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Bestor, Arthur Eugene, David Jacks of Monterey, and Lee L. Jacks his Daughter – unbound and bound copies 1945 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Klass, Bertrand, A Handbook for Group Discussion Leaders (American Ideals and American Industry) 1954 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - American Ideals and American Industry workbook, discussion handbook, correspondence (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - The Stanford American Ideals Program; Experimental Industrial Course 1953 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Life under Communism, a Series of Experimental Discussion Programs – (1953, The Fund for Adult Education, Pasadena, CA) (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - SUP Business Files: Composing Room – Equipment (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - SUP Business Files: S.U. Departmental Publications – syllabus (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - SUP Business Files: Bindery (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - SUP Business Files: Bindery equipment, 1969- (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - SUP Business Files: Bindery equipment, 1946-1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – automobile (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – compensation, 1944-1951 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - SUP Business Files: Camera room – equipment (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - SUP Business Files: Composing room – equipment (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - SUP Business Files: Hi-Fi system (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - SUP Business Files: Office equipment – Auto-typist (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - SUP Business Files: Photolith typing equipment (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - SUP Business Files: Pressroom equipment, 1966-76 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - SUP Business Files: Pressroom equipment, 1947-65 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - SUP Business Files: Proof room – equipment (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - SUP Business Files: Record player and amplifier (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – provisional – merchandise, 1947-1950 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – merchandise, 1939-1946 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – retirement insurance plan (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - SUP Business Files: Contracts – contract forms – author royalties, 1949-1955 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - SUP Business Files: Insurance – surety bond coverage (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - SUP Business Files: Inventory – books taken from work in progress, 1952-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - SUP Business Files: Inventory – records (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - SUP Business Files: Inventory – stores (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - SUP Business Files: Financial statements – annual (August), 1934-1943 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - SUP Business Files: IBM – tests-card order department, 1951-1959 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Wrenn, C. Gilbert, Building Self-Confidence pamphlet, various eds. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Wrenn, Practical Study Aids pamphlet, various editions (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Wrenn, Study-Habits Inventory pamphlet with scoring key 1941 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Wrenn, Study Hints for High School Students pamphlet, various eds. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Wrenn, C. Gilbert and Luella Cole, Reading Rapidly and Well pamphlet, various eds. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Zyve, D.L., Stanford Scientific Aptitude Test and manual, various eds. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Zyve, Stanford Scientific Aptitude Test French translations (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Zyve, Stanford Scientific Aptitude Test Portuguese translation (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Zyve, Stanford Scientific Aptitude Test new printings: 1955, 1962, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - SVIC-SCII miscellany and computer printouts (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - SVIB-SCII manuals, etc., Consulting Psychologists Press (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - SVIB miscellany (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Revised Stanford Profile Scales of Hypnotic Susceptibility – scoring booklets (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – assorted publications (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Fitzwater, James P., Educational Film Appraisal Scale (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – Forms I & II (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – Forms A & B (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – Form C (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – 1982 printing, booklets and blanks (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – Forms I & II, 1967 revision (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Weitzenhoffer, Stanford Hypnotic Susceptibility Scale – Form C (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Cooper and Robins, The Term Paper, A Manual and Model (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wrenn and Larsen, Studying Effectively 1962, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Wrenn, Study Habits Inventory – Spanish translations (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Wrenn, University Training and Vocational Outlets (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Wrenn and Larsen, Studying Effectively – Norwegian, Icelandic, Spanish, Thai translations (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Wrenn and Larsen, Studying Effectively, through 1961 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Tyler-Kimber Study Skills Test (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Weatherbe, A Checklist for School Health Services (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Willoughby, Emotional Maturity Scale (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Worthingham, Upper and Lower Extremity Muscle and Innervation Charts, multiple eds. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - White, Personal Data Blank (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Working, Binomial and Poisson Distributions (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Tomlin, The Best Thing to Do (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Consulting Psychologists Press catalogs 1986-1988 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Catalogs from other Presses (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Hansen, Jo-Ida C., Strong-Hansen Occupational Guide (Consulting Psychologists Press, 1987) (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Hirsh, Sandra Krebs, Using the Strong in Organizations (Consulting Psychologists Press, 1986) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Mears, Eliot Grinnell, Tentative Findings on a Survey of Race Relations 1925 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Mead, Margaret, The Study of National Character 1953 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Hoss – Stanford University map postcard 1950 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio M., Folklore in European Literature 1935 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Pierson, William H., Te Pacific Northwest (map) 1945 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lutz and Quinn, The Reichstag election of March 5, 1933 1943 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Klass, Bertrand, The American Ideals Program: session booklets and handbook (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Shock, Nathan W., Journal of Gerontology Author Index to Current Publications 1953-1961 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Shock, Nathan W., Journal of Gerontology Author Index to Current Publications 1961-1963 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Working, Holbrook, Guide to Utilization of the Binomial and Poisson Distributions in Industrial Quality Control (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Williams, Joseph – maps of the world (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Scaff, Alvin H., La Response des Iles Philippines au Communisme (French translation of The Philippine Answer to Communism – mimeographed, with cover letter from Lawrence R. Houston, C.I.A. 1959) (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Shafer, George D., Physiology 101: A Syllabus Guide 1934 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Bell, Hugh, The Adjustment Inventory: Students report forms and test booklets (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Bell, Hugh, The Adjustment Inventory: Students scoring keys (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Bell, The Adjustment Inventory: Students manuals (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Bell, The Adjustment Inventory: Students answer sheets (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Bell, The Adjustment Inventory: Adults test booklets & manuals (Box 16, Folder 22)